herbs-info.com 2019-08-28

# Privacy Policy - herbs-info.com

**Last Update: Feb 19th, 2019** \- "Google Ads: Opting Out" section added. Prior version: July 15th 2018 

## 1\. Introduction

www.herbs-info.com ("This Website") is operated by Alex Newman. Any reference to "I" or "me" in this privacy policy refers to Alex Newman. Your information privacy is important to me. Here is This Website's privacy policy. 

## 2\. Modification

I reserve the right to make updates to this Privacy Policy at any time, and without giving prior notice, by simply posting an updated privacy policy here at this page. This policy will be viewable on the site from the link at the foot of each of the site's other pages. Please check periodically for updates. Your use of the site constitutes your acceptance of the current Privacy Policy. 

Click [here](http://www.herbs-info.com/policies/privacy-old.html) to view previous privacy policy information. 

## 3\. Email List

This Website may feature an email list and email signup forms enabling you to subscribe. Our email lists are managed by Aweber, Inc. and hosted on their servers - and the policy governing the manner in which such email addresses are utilized can be found at their email permission guidelines page here: <http://www.aweber.com/permission.htm>

By submitting your email address you consent to receiving our emails until you unsubscribe. Emails may contain informational as well as promotional content (for which we may earn commissions on product sales). 

When you sign up for our email list, the email address you provide is stored and managed in our Aweber.com account. Aweber also stores IP address and geolocation information such as city, state and zip code (personally identifiable information - "PII"). This information is accessible to our team but is only used for the purposes of sending emails through Aweber. We may make a "safety backup" of the email list but we do not do additional data mining, nor do we distribute, sell or transfer your personal information to others. Your information is retained by us until deleted. We take the best reasonable measures we can to ensure that your information is safe: Physical locks protect our premises, strong passwords are used, and access to the information is restricted to our team, who have been given a strict training in data security best practices. Note that some of our team members are located outside of the EU, however they are under strict instructions not to copy or move any PII outside of the Aweber App. 

We do not add subscribers to our list unless they have requested it by entering their email address. In the unlikely event that someone else has entered your email address by accident and you start receiving email from us, simply unsubscribe using the method below.

If you decide you no longer wish to receive emails from us, **you can unsubscribe easily (withdraw consent) using the unsubscribe link provided at the foot of every email we send**. Unsubscribing removes your email address from our mail-out list immediately; however your information is accessible to us in Aweber's database until we manually delete it. "Unsubscribed" email addresses, together with the other personal information recorded as mentioned above, are manually deleted from our Aweber database (every 3 weeks approximately) and once deleted, this info is no longer accessible ("forgotten"). We can provide an expedited deletion if requested by email ("right of erasure"). 

EU subscribers can also request a copy of the information we hold about them and can request rectification. 

**Hello Bar:** If you sign up for our email list using the red "Hello Bar" exit popup, your email address is additionally stored within the HelloBar app, which is synced to Aweber's API. 

## 4\. Children's Online Privacy

This Website does not knowingly collect information from, or sell to, children under the age of 13. 

## 5\. Third Party Services

As you use This Website, information may be collected using various systems such as, but not limited to, cookies, server logs, Google Analytics and pixel tracking. Data collection and processing practices are set forth below. 

**Log files**

As with most web sites, logs are automatically created which register the IP address and other information such as the date and time of access of This Website. I may use this information for general administrative, diagnostic or market research purposes. This web site uses common server-side statistics utilities, such as Awstats, that are provided by This Website's hosting provider. These utilities provide user demographics such as the user's country and city of location, IP address, browser type, and keywords used in searches used to find this site - and I may use such data for the purposes of optimizing the "performance" and quality of This Website, and for market research. 

**Google Adsense**

Google Adsense is one of the major ad types that we display on this website. Google's own words about this: "We encourage you to link to this user-facing page <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/> explaining how Google manages data in its ads products. Doing so will meet the requirement of our EU User Consent Policy to give your users information about Google’s uses of their personal data.” 

**Google Analytics**

This Website uses Google Analytics in order to track visitor activity with a view to observing and improve site performance, and for market research. This retains information that Google does not deem to be "Personally Identifying Information" (PII). Google Analytics uses cookies to measure user interactions on websites. Full details on GA cookie use here: <https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage>

Google Analytics may use cookies - and the information (such as, but not limited to, IP address, geographic location (town and country), date and time of access, time spent on site, keywords used in searches to find This Website) generated by the use of Google Analytics is transmitted to, and stored by Google Inc. I have access to this data but have no control over how this information is used by Google Inc. Deletion of personally identifying information is available upon request. Google Analytics' Policies can be viewed here: [http://www.google.com/analytics/](https://www.google.com/analytics/)

**Google Ads: Opting out**

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!%2F) or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on. 

**Facebook Fans**

If you have "liked" and are therefore a member of one of our Facebook fan pages, we are able to view your Facebook profile with the same level of privilege as any other regular Facebook user is able to view it. We do not scrape, harvest, copy or process this information in any special way and we do not store it in any archive other than the Facebook fan page itself. Our interaction with our fans consists of moderating comments, occasional extended dialogue and occasionally banning users. Removing yourself from one of our fan pages is simple, just visit the fan page and 'unlike'. 

**Facebook tracking pixel**

We do not currently utilize Facebook Pixel or other tracking pixels on any of our websites.

**Facebook custom audiences**

We do not currently utilize Facebook custom audiences

## 6\. Cookies

\- please review our full **cookie policy** at the link at the foot of this page.

## 7\. Information Security

I have taken reasonable measures to protect such information of yours - whether personally or non-personally identifying, as may reside on my computer systems - such as password access, firewall, and physical locks. However, please note that no internet data transmission or physical data storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

## 8\. Links

This Website may contain links to and from other Websites, including advertisements. While I do my best only to link to quality resources, I am not responsible for the practices, privacy policy, terms of service or content of those sites. 

* * * * *

Privacy Policy (you are here) | [Cookie Policy](http://www.herbs-info.com/policies/cookie-policy.html) | [GDPR](http://www.herbs-info.com/policies/GDPR-compliance-roadmap.html) | [About This Site](http://www.herbs-info.com/about.html) | [Homepage](http://www.herbs-info.com/)

_© herbs-info.com 2018_
